《太空堡垒卡拉狄加》 前情提要
STARBUCK: Previously on Battlestar Galactica.
我们还没正式介绍过 我是李奥本
We haven't been properly introduced. I'm Leoben.
我期待与你多待上一会呢  星芭
I'm looking forward to spending a little more time with you, Starbuck.
我们还有很多事要谈
We have a lot to talk about!
那将是很有趣的
It's gonna be fun.
恭喜你  指挥官
Congratulations, Commander.
帕伽索斯由你指挥
The Pegasus is your command.
我看到一个巨大的星体
SKULLS: Hey, I am picking up a large planetary body.
它是可居住的 我们也许找到了一个可供居住的星球
It's habitable. We may have just found a world that can support human life.
我清楚自己心中认为在那个行星定居
ROSLIN: I know in my gut that settling on this planet's
对于人类来说意味着灾难
gonna mean disaster for humanity,
不然我也不想说我想赢得这次选举了
and I will not say otherwise just to win an election.
我接受科波十二个殖民地总统之职
I take the office of President of the 12 Colonies of Kobol.
我将要发布我的第一个命令
And I am going to sign my first executive order
要求舰队立即建立殖民区定居点
requiring to immediately establish settlements
在我们现在的新卡布里卡星球上
on the planet we have come to know as New Caprica.
如果你想要下去  那就下去吧  请便
If you want to move down there, go ahead, be my guest.
到下面和男人们鬼混去吧
Go down and cat around with all the men.
少  我喜欢的人是你
Saul, I want you.
至少  一个安全的天堂  我们能把它称作家
CALLY: At last, a safe haven we can call home.
我的天
Oh, my Gods!
这是赛昂舰队  他们找到我们了
The Cylon fleet, they found us.
我们必须离开这里  长官
APOLLO: We have to get out of here, sir.
我们不能扔下我们的人
We can't just leave all those people behind.
我们什么也做不了
There's nothing we can do.
我们不在战斗状态  长官
We're in no shape for a fight, sir.
他们会被消灭的
ADAMA: They'll be wiped out.
我们没有选择
We don't have a choice.
我们现在必须离开这里!
We need to get out of here right now!
开始跳跃准备  我们要离开了
Begin jump prep. We're leaving.
但是我们会回来的
But we'll be back.
赛昂人刚刚跳跃到轨道上
The Cylons just jumped into orbit.
并且舰队跳跃走了 他们已经离开我们了
And the fleet's jumped away. They've left us.
我代表12殖民地的人民...
BALTAR: On behalf of the people of the 12 Colonies,
投降
I surrender.
我正在找卡拉・瑟瑞丝
I'm looking for Kara Thrace.
每次他们把你带出这间拘禁室
Do you know that every time they take you out of this cell,
我们就来这里改变那些细微的
we come in here and we change those little hashmarks
你隐藏在日期里的标记
on your little calendar there you're trying to hide?
马铃薯  肉汤  甚至还有一些胡萝卜
Potatoes, gravy, even some carrots.
老天  我们感谢你满桌子的慷慨
Heavenly Father, we thank you for the bounty of this table.
爽
ELLEN: Yes.
好爽
Yes.
来吧!别停下
Come on, don't stop.
来吧!来吧! 狗娘养的!
Come on, come on, you son of a bitch!
狗娘养的!
You son of a bitch!
好的!
Oh, yeah.
啊  宝贝  啊!
Oh, boy.
好!我们装备好了
All right, we're armed.
他们回航了  我们行动吧!
They're inbound. Let's move!
我需要一把刀
I need a knife.
谢谢
Thank you.
别客气
You're welcome.
我必须说  我很喜欢这样
I must say, I quite enjoyed that.
我很高兴
I'm so glad.
还有  我何时能够得到我想要的东西?
And when do I get what I want?
我相信现在就可以了
I believe that's happening right now.
我们今天重新审查了你的案件
We reviewed your case today,
我不得不说重审委员会对此很失望
and I must say there was great disappointment on the review committee.
来吧
Come on.
我们会按程序处理  这可能会花上一个小时
We've got to get you processed. It'll take an hour or so.
官僚主义就是这样子的
Bureaucracy must be served.
但是如果你运气好的话 你可以在晚饭时间回家
But if you're lucky, you'll get home by dinnertime.
上校 来吧
Colonel, come on.
我不会一直把这扇门开着的
I'm not gonna hold this door open forever.
注意 新卡布里卡市民们 很快 饮水将…
MAN ON PA: Attention, New Capricans. Effective immediately, a pot of water
在双数日期提供给双数编号的市民
will be given to residents in even-numbered pods on even-numbered days
在单数日期提供给单数编号的市民 供给量为…
and odd-numbered pods on odd-numbered days. Rationing will be...
少!
Saul!
亲爱的 他们都对你做了什么?
Oh, sweetheart. What did they do to you?
没事了  我出来了 就是这样了
It's all right. I'm out, and that's all that matters.
我们离开这里
Come on, now, let's get out of here.
好的
Okay.
好  准备好了吗?  就是现在
Okay, ready? Now!
他妈的怎么回事?  快  快!
Oh, for frak sakes. Come on! Come on!
这有用吗?
Is that thing gonna work or what?
起爆正是时候  走  走!
It worked that time. Come on. Go, go!
他妈的起义者
Frakking insurgents.
你今晚看上去...如此可爱
You look so lovely tonight.
我不久就能再一次见到你了  卡拉
I'll see you soon, Kara.
不着急
Take your time.
赛昂人占领…
ROSLIN: "One hundred and thirty fourth day
新卡布里卡的第134天
"of the Cylon occupation of New Caprica.
今天是火星日
"Today is Mars Day.
似乎是祭典战神的日子
"Somehow it seems appropriate to honor the God of War
感觉每天都处在永不停息的战争中
"on a day when it feels like perpetual war
这是我们的现实
"is the only realistic prospect for us.
自从卡拉狄加四个月前离开以后 我们与失去了和它的联系
"We've had no contact with Galactica since it left four months ago.
但是我绝不相信  阿达玛已经抛弃了我们
"But I refuse to believe that Adama has abandoned us.
无论何时何地  只要有可能的话
"Our insurgency has been striking back against the Cylons
我们将一直反抗赛昂人的占领
"whenever and wherever possible.
虽然这种攻击是微不足道的
"Although at times, these attacks seem like futile gestures,
但是我相信  这对于士气是至关重要的
"I believe that they are critical to morale,
这也是为了保持希望
"to maintaining some measure of hope.
但为了使这种反抗有更大的影响
"But in order for the insurgency to have a more meaningful impact,
我们需要攻击一个引人注目的目标
"we need to strike a high-profile target.
这不仅仅是为了杀死赛昂人 因为他们不会死
"It is simply not enough to kill Cylons, because they don't die.
他们可以复活 他们可以继续在我们中间行走
"They resurrect themselves, and they continue to walk among us.
这很恐怖
"It is horrifying.
赛昂占领当局继续完善对城市的控制
"The Cylon Occupation Authority continues to exert complete control
并且我们完全受他们的支配
"over the city, and we remain at their mercy.
盖尤斯・波塔尔总统领导下的殖民地政府
"The Colonial Government, under President Gaius Baltar,
只是个傀儡政权
"functions in name only. "
让我们回顾一下 为什么我们在这里?
Let's review why we're here, shall we?
我们应该给人民传播"上帝"的声音
We're supposed to bring the word of God to the people, right?
保护人类免遭天谴
To save humanity from damnation
把上帝的爱带给这些贫穷、愚昧的人们
by bringing the love of God to these poor benighted people.
我们在这里是因为大多数的赛昂人…
We're here because the majority of the Cylon
认为攻击人类是一个错误
felt that the slaughter of mankind had been a mistake.
我们来这里是为了寻求一个和平生存的方式
We're here to find a new way to live in peace,
因为上帝希望我们活下去
as God wants us to live.
到目前为止  这看上去是个不错的开端
And it's been a fun ride so far.
但是我想要澄清我们的目标
But I want to clarify our objectives.
如果我们带着上帝的箴言
If we're bringing the word of God,
那么
then it follows
我们就必须采取任何必要的方式
that we should employ any means necessary to do so.
竭尽所能  达到我们的目的
Any means. Yes.
恐惧才能产生信仰 就像我所理解的
Fear is a key article of faith, as I understand it.
或许是时候给人们的身心
So perhaps it's time to instill a little more fear
慢慢灌输一些恐惧了
into the people's hearts and minds.
让我们处死波塔尔
Let's execute Baltar.
什么? 什么?!
What, what?
这不会发生的
That's not gonna happen.
仅仅因为他是你最喜欢的玩具
Just because he's your favorite toy
所以就不允许我们在这里干涉更重大的事情
shouldn't be allowed to interfere with the larger issues here.
我想我已经与你们合作了
I think that I have cooperated...
盖尤斯和我是一体的
Gaius is with me.
任何想要挑战的人必须先要对付我
Anyone who wants to challenge that will have to deal with me.
好吧  没有关系
No, it doesn't matter.
如果我们一开始就杀了他 那会有效果的
If we'd killed him at the beginning, it might have worked.
但是现在  大多数人认为他是一个叛徒
But now most humans think of him as a traitor
或许正在翘首以盼他的死讯呢
and would actually cheer his death.
很好  很好  我们不杀波塔尔
Fine, fine. We don't kill Baltar.
我们围捕那些反叛者的领袖 然后公开处死他们
We round up the leaders of the insurgency, and we execute them publicly.
我们随机在街上围捕
We round up, at random, groups off the street,
然后公开处死他们
and we execute them publicly.
发个消息说刽子手来了
Send a message that the gloves are coming off.
叛乱现在停止了 要不然我们就开始减少人口数量
The insurgency stops now or else we start reducing the human population
让人数降到一个更有利于管理的水平
to a more manageable size.
我不知道是多少 少于1000人吧
I don't know, say less than 1,000.
我们不能再做屠夫了
We need to stop being butchers.
重点应放在这里 开始一种新生活
The entire point of coming here was to start a new way of life,
忘记过去我们和人类长久以来的冲突
to push past the conflict that separated us from humans for so long.
我们得到了什么?
CAVIL: And what has it gotten us?
这看上去不像是他们在欢迎我们...
It's not like they welcomed us with...
妈的别介意 你们都生活在一个幻想的世界中
Oh, frak it, never mind. You're all living in a fantasy world.
在那里说胡话
Consider the irony in that!
妄想的机器
Delusional machines.
宇宙接下来会是什么样子的呢?
What's the universe gonna come up with next?
这是值得的吗  卡布里卡?
Is it really worth it, Caprica?
那个人真的值得你失去所有这些吗?
Is the love of that man really worth possibly losing all of this?
如果你曾经有过真爱
If you ever experienced love,
你就不会问了
you wouldn't have to ask.
在最近几个月里 赛昂人招募和训练人类
ROSLIN: "In recent months, the Cylons have been recruiting and training humans
试图建立一支由人类组成的警察部队
"in an attempt to establish a human police force.
很难想起人类比赛昂人
"It is hard to think of anything more despicable
做的更卑鄙的事情了
"than humans doing the dirty work of the Cylons.
赛昂使人们相信这样做仅仅是为了…
"Led to believe they were merely taking the civilian security
协助赛昂人保证平民的安全
"out of the hands of the Cylons,
很多人类警察
"the members of the human police
已经成为赛昂人的走狗
"have since become an extension of the Cylons' corporeal authority.
他们的名字都被保密
"And while their names are kept deeply confidential,
毫无疑问有些人是我们最不希望看到的
"there's no question some of them are people we might least expect.
我们中的上百人已经被赛昂人逮捕了
"Hundreds of us have been rounded up by the Cylons,
被拘禁  审讯  折磨
"held in detention, questioned, tortured.
而另一些人失踪了
"Others have simply vanished.
最近几周
"In recent weeks,
从波塔尔政府部门的一个线人那里
"we've been gaining access to some very important documents
我们获得了一些非常重要的文件
"from a source within Baltar's administration.
没有人知道他是谁
"No one knows who this mysterious benefactor is,
但是他用密码和抵抗者联系
"but he communicates with the insurgents by means of a secret signal.
我们每天为那些冒生命危险对抗赛昂人的...
"We pray every day for the men and women who risk their lives
男男女女们祈祷
"to fight the Cylons.
他们失去了一切 只是为了获得一些小小的希望
"They have everything to lose and such little hope of something to gain. "
嘿  杰克
Hey, Jake.
我们睡觉吧
There we go.
看来今晚只有妈妈陪你睡了
It looks like Mommy's gonna get some sleep tonight after all.
有时候我憎恨这里的一切
You know, sometimes I hate everything about this place.
有时候...不可思议
But sometimes it's magic.
我要走了 我在几小时后回来
I gotta go. Be back in a couple hours.
这些日子你可能不回来了  对吗?
One of these days you're just not gonna come back, are you?
就这样消失了
You'll just vanish, and that'll be it.
我再也不会见到你了
I'll never see you again.
尼克永远也不会真的知道他的父亲了
Nick will never know his father.
我保证就几小时
A couple hours, promise.
很高兴见到你  上校
Good to see you, Colonel.
很高兴被你看见
It's good to be seen.
我知道你想知道  所以我就直说了
I know you're wondering, so I'll save you the trouble.
眼睛没了
The eye is gone.
脱落掉到地板上
Ripped it right out, onto the floor,
拿起来看
picked it up and showed it to me.
像个煮熟的鸡蛋
It looked like a hardboiled egg.
今天可是个大日子
Big boom today.
希望对你们也是
Hope that was you two.
喔  是的  重型突袭机也是
Oh, yeah. A heavy Raider, too.
我们下一个目标是什么?
Good man. What's our next target?
这是今天拿到的
Well, we got these today.
是新卡布里卡警察学校
They're security plans for the graduation ceremony
毕业典礼上的安保计划
of the New Caprica Police Academy.
是从政府文件中拿来的
These are right out of the Ministry files.
你从哪里得到这些材料的?
Where are you getting this stuff?
谁是你的线人?
Who's your source?
我不知道 消息来源不告诉我他们的名字
I have no idea. The source won't tell me what their name is.
或许对我们更安全
It's probably safer for all of us.
我们几周来一直获得这些材料
We've been getting stuff like this for weeks.
人们为赛昂人工作 搞得你想要呕吐
Humans working for the Cylons, makes me wanna puke.
是的  所有占领者的头头脑脑们都会在毕业典礼上露脸
Yeah, well, all of the top Occupation brass is gonna be at the graduation,
甚至...波塔尔总统
even President Baltar.
盖尤斯・波塔尔?
Gaius Baltar?
是的  长官
Yes, sir.
我想我们也可以给他来一枪
I think we can get a shot at him, too.
但想要避免人员伤亡的话很困难
The problem is, it's gonna be tough avoiding human casualties.
那就不要避免伤亡  给他们发消息
Don't avoid them! Send a message.
"你与赛昂人合作  你就是目标"
You work with the Cylons, you're a target.
赛昂人可不加什么区分  我们也没有!
No boundaries for the Cylons, there's no boundaries for us!
任何能够干掉盖尤斯・波塔尔那狗娘养的办法都值得尝试
Anything we can do to nail that son of a bitch, Gaius Baltar, is worth doing.
无线电监听如何了?
Where are we on the wireless?
嗯...没有  每天我们都试图联系猛禽机
Nowhere. Every day we try and contact the Raptor,
每天赛昂人都干扰了频率
and every day the Cylons jam the transmission.
我问过我们内部的情报来源
I've asked the inside source to tell us
告诉我们赛昂人哪一波段的封锁是最弱的
which of the Cylon jamming frequencies are the weakest,
但是目前为止  我什么都不知道
but so far I've got nothing.
你们在做梦 那里没有猛禽  对不?
You guys are dreaming. There's no Raptor there, okay?
过去四个月都没有出现过
There hasn't been one for the past four months, either.
卡拉狄加不会再回来了 他们不会了
Galactica's not coming back. They're not.
接受事实吧    闭上你的嘴
Accept it. You watch your frakking mouth!
每天都有猛禽战机在外轨道监听无线电信号
There's a Raptor out there every day, listening for our wireless call.
他在外面 这是计划好的
It's out there because that was the plan if anything happened.
那个老头子不会把我们留给赛昂人
And it's out there because the old man isn't just gonna leave us to the Cylons!
上校  那个老头子把我留给了赛昂人了
The old man left me to the Cylons, Colonel.
如果它不是为了我的妻子 那个高贵的下面痒痒的人
And if it wasn't for my wife being a royal pain in the ass
拒绝让她离开
and refusing to let it go,
我早在这一年里死了
I would be dead a year now.
有没有卡拉的消息?
Any word on Kara?
没有 四个月了
Nothing in four months.
嘿  宝贝  我回家了
LEOBEN: Hi, honey. I'm home.
你杀我  我下载到新躯壳
You kill me, I download,
我回来  我们重新开始
I come back, we start over.
这已经是第五次了
Five times now.
我在试图帮你  卡拉
I'm trying to help you, Kara.
我只是想让你看到你生命的真相
I only want you to see the truth of your life,
你痛苦和挣扎了那么久
the reason why you suffered and you struggled for so long.
这就是为什么上帝把我派到你身边
That's why God sent me to you.
这就是为什么上帝希望我们在一起的原因
That's why God wants us to be together.
对
You're right.
我听你的  我会做的
And I hear you. I do.
很好
Okay.
那么  谢谢你
So, thank you.
谢谢容忍我
Thank you for putting up with me.
对不起
I'm so sorry.
不要再提了  卡拉
Put it down, Kara.
放下它吧
Just put it down.
我是个很有耐心的男人
I'm a patient man.
你不是个男人
You're not a man.
我愿意等  你只是需要更多的时间
I'm willing to wait. You just need more time.
我才不需要更多的时间 这永远也不会发生的
I don't need more frakking time. It's never gonna happen.
这当然会发生 你会挽着我的肩膀
Of course it's gonna happen. You're gonna hold me in your arms.
你会拥抱我 你会和我说你爱我
You're gonna embrace me. You're gonna tell me that you love me.
我看到过的
I've seen it.
你疯了
You're insane.
知道了上帝的真面目就知道了什么是疯狂
To know the face of God is to know madness.
我要睡觉了
I'm going to bed.
如果你和我一起睡的话  那就太好不过了
Be nice if you joined me.
两种方式任选一种 反正你会和我一起共度今宵
Either way, you're spending the night with me.
我真的喜欢你  卡拉・瑟瑞丝
I do love you, Kara Thrace.
晚安
Good night.
放我出去!
Let me out!
让我离开这里!
Let me out of here!
我不属于这里  让我出去!
I don't belong here! Let me out!
让我出去!
Let me out!
赛道 调整中心航线20度
MAN 1: Racetrack, adjust your center line 20 degrees.
雪鸟3号 得到信息
MAN 2: Snowbird Three, get in formation.
好的 我的雪鸟 让我们完成这个练习
RACETRACK: Okay, Snowbirds, let's nail this exercise.
我们要这样做多少次
MAN 3: How many times are we gonna run this thing?
什么 你还没有得到乐趣吗
RACETRACK: What, you're not having fun?
集中精力 雪鸟
Come on, focus, Snowbirds!
雪鸟 这是卡拉狄加  重新编队
HELO: Snowbirds, Galactica. Regroup into deployment formation
向1号区域进发
and proceed to position one.
雪鸟1号 呼叫 雪鸟
Snowbird One to Snowbirds,
8秒钟后到达
drop point in eight seconds.
好的  我是雪鸟  让我们飞向预定目标
Okay, Snowbirds, let's get this deployment bang on.
上将正在看着我们
The Admiral's watching every move.
收到 凯
RACETRACK: Roger, Kat.
我们听你的指挥
We go on your command.
炸弹舱门开启
Bomb bay doors opened.
所有蝮蛇 现在出击  现在  现在!
All Vipers break. Now, now, now!
发射导弹 听我的命令射击
RACETRACK: Deploy drones on my mark.
三  二  一  开火!
Three, two, one, mark!
混蛋!
Frak me!
上帝 我是雪鸟4号 发生了什么事
Gods damn it, Snowbird Four, what the hell happened?
你能回答吗 雪鸟
Can the chatter, Snowbirds.
我是CAG  终止任务
This is the CAG. Abort maneuver.
我再说一次  空中编队  终止任务
I say again, decoy squadron abort maneuver.
收到 老大
MAN 4: Roger that, leader.
雪鸟 回航 终止演练 等待进一步指示
HELO: Snowbirds, fall back. Abort the drill. Await further instructions.
靠 打到我机翼了
RACETRACK: Frak, they're on my wing.
卡拉狄加 我是凯 外面真是一团糟
KAT: Galactica, Kat. It is a mess out here.
我们的导弹到处乱飞
We've got decoy drones heading every which way.
请求指示
Request instructions.
收到  凯  终止计划
Roger that, Kat. Abort acknowledged.
不管怎么样  你都能得到燃料  把你的飞鸟开回家吧
You're approaching bingo fuel anyway. Bring your birds back home.
打住吧
Belay that.
停止执行最后的命令  待命
Strike my last. Stand by.
派出加油机
Launch the tanker bird.
让他们练习练习在飞行中加油
Let them practice their in-flight refueling before they recover the drones
然后让他们再练习一次
and run the exercise one more time.
是  长官  现在已经16次了  长官
Yes, sir. 16 times now, sir.
下一次就是17次了  对吧?
The next one will be 17, won't it?
是的  长官
Yes, sir.
发射加油机
Launch the tanker.
卡拉狄加  所有单位
All units, Galactica.
恢复导弹攻击 准备进行下一次练习
Recover drones and prepare to run training mission again.
我们发射加油机了
We're launching the tanker bird.
加油机?    一旦你从加油机那里得到了补给
Tanker? Once you've tanked up,
回到阿尔法区域 准备第17次练习
head back to position Alpha and prepare for training run 17.
卡拉狄加通话完毕
Galactica out.
他们在做什么?
What the frak are they doing over there?
这是指挥官  我要和上将通话
This is the Commander. Get the Admiral on the line.
上将  考虑到我们的飞行员
Admiral, considering how long our pilots
在外飞行的时间 我建议我们召回战机
have been in the air, I suggest we recall the birds
放弃训练
and scrub the training exercise.
如果我们不能在训练演习里做到这点
If we can't do this in a training scenario,
我们怎么能够在遇到赛昂突袭机的时候赢得胜利?
how the hell are we supposed to pull this off
让他们踢我们的屁股吗?
with Cylon raiders on our asses?
告诉我!  你想从我这里得到什么?
Huh? Tell me! What the frak do you want from me?
我不知道为何用我们一半的兵力为了这样的假设去冒险
I don't know how we're supposed to do any of this crap at half strength!
碰撞 我们发生碰撞了
KAT: Collision! We've had a collision!
告诉我你的位置  凯
APOLLO: Give me your status, Kat.
兵戈  沃利  跟我说话
KAT: Bingo, Wally, speak to me!
我失去了飞行控制!
BINGO: I'm losing flight control!
我收到红色警报 到处都是
I've got red lights all across the board!
凯  我在翻转 我失去动力了 我的机翼断了
Kat, I'm in a wild spin! I'm losing hydraulics. My wing is going.
卡拉狄加 我是凯 我宣布进入紧急状态
Galactica, Kat. I'm declaring an emergency.
要求两架飞鸟优先降落
Request priority landing for two bent birds.
让他们进来    是  长官
Pull them in! Yes, sir.
收到  凯  把你的飞鸟带回家
Roger that, Kat. Bring your birds back home.
等候下一步指示
Further instructions to follow.
整件事情就像发疯了
This whole thing is frakking insane.
两艘船 只有一半的兵力
We've got two ships at half strength.
我们的船员有一年半的时间没有行动过了
We've got crews that haven't seen action in a year and a half,
而你的问题是把他们看成没有足够努力地训练
and you're acting like the only problem is they're not working hard enough?
你最近有没有照过镜子?
Have you taken a look at yourself in the mirror lately?
你很虚弱!  身心皆是
You're weak, soft, mentally and physically.
这不是关于我的
This isn't about me.
你已经做了四个月整合方案
You've had four months to get your act together.
目前为止  你所能做的
And so far all you've been able to frakking do
就是抱怨这有多困难
is to complain and whine about how hard it is.
你就想吧
Well, guess what?
越想越困难  你明白我的意思吗?
It's gonna get a lot harder. Do you understand me?
现在我希望能够说服你 让你这个胖家伙离开这里
Now, I want you to turn around and get your fat ass out of here.
让你的人准备好!  不然我就找一个能够做到的人
Get your men ready, or I'll find someone who can.
解散!
Dismissed!
漂亮 安德斯
DUCK: Good shot, Anders.
去前面设防
PLAYER 1: Go ahead and set it up.
给我球 快
SAM: Move inside! Give me the ball, right here!
我不喜欢这样  上校
I don't like this one, Colonel.
我想我们是这里越线的人
I think we're the ones crossing the line here.
这是唯一能够起作用的方式 孩子们作主了
It's the only way it's gonna work. The kid's got access and clearance.
就准备这样了一旦你开始了你就不能回头了
We've got to be square on this. You can't back out once you've started.
我没有回头
I'm not backing out.
这是不对的  上校 你知道的  不是吗?
It's wrong, Colonel. You know that, don't you?
他是个战士  军士长
He's a soldier, Chief.
这已经不是我们第一次把战士派上有去无回的战场中了
It's not the first time we've sent a soldier on a one-way mission.
这你是知道的  不是吗?
You know that, don't you?
这不同
This is different.
这是我们干掉盖尤斯・波塔尔的最好机会
This is our best chance to take out Gaius Baltar.
或许唯一的机会 我们确定我们能成功
It may be the only one, and we're sure as frak gonna take it.
自从他们杀了Nora
Ever since they killed Nora,
我就再也没有什么牵绊了
I've got nothing to live for.
快 回防
PLAYER 2: Let's go, set it up.
看着我的眼睛你说你会忠于此事
Now look me in the eye and you tell me that you are committed to this.
我会忠于
I'm committed.
愿神与你同在
May the Gods be with you.
上校  有些事情你最好还是不要去做
Some things you just don't do, Colonel,
即使在战争中也不要
not even in war.
当你在拘禁室的时候或许你的感觉就会不同
Well, maybe you'll feel different when you're sitting in detention.
杜克自愿去的  他已经走了
Duck volunteered. He's going.
这很难说 出口
ADAMA: It's a hard thing to say,
但是看上去我再也不了解我的儿子了
but it seems like I don't know who my son is anymore.
同样也不了解这艘船的船员了
The same goes for the crew, the ship.
我感到很孤单 或许除了你
I feel pretty much alone. Except maybe for you.
我希望我能够回到一年前
I wish I could come back a year
告诉阿达玛上将这次谈话
and tell that Admiral Adama about this conversation.
一年可是很长的时间啊
A year's a long time.
我能问你一些事情吗?  很私人的问题
Can I ask you something very personal?
你把人们扔在新卡布里卡会不会感到有罪恶感?
Do you feel guilty about leaving the people behind on New Caprica?
我不做有罪的事
I don't do guilt.
你知道 一年前…
You know, a year ago,
当你把我关到小屋里的时候 我处于一个十字路口
when you put me in this cell, I was at a crossroads.
我坐在那里几周 对发生在我身上的事儿
I sat in here for weeks, just consumed with rage
大呼小叫
at all the things that had happened to me.
对这一点来说  我开始感到惭愧
And at some point I realized it was all just guilt.
我对自己做出的感到愤怒
I was angry at myself for the choices I had made.
背叛我的人 丢了我的孩子
Betraying my people, losing my baby.
所以...我要做出选择
So I had a choice.
我要么向前走  要么沉溺于过去
I could either move forward or stay in the past.
但是向前走的唯一的方法 就是原谅自己
But the only way to move forward was to forgive myself.
你知道  我不认为我们能够活下来
You know, I don't think we can survive,
我不认为舰队或者卡拉狄加或者新卡布里卡上的人能够活下来
I don't think the Fleet or Galactica or the people on New Caprica can survive
除非上面的人能找到一个方法来原谅自己
unless the man at the top finds a way to forgive himself.
我们两个飞行员差点死了
Two of our pilots almost get killed
因为他们在驾驶舱里待了11个小时
because they've been in the cockpit for 11 hours,
他想踢爆我的卵蛋
and he wants to bust my balls.
你很虚弱 你能相信吗?
"You're soft. " Can you believe that?
什么?
What?
你同意了  是这样吗?
Oh, you agree, is that it?
忘了它吧  我期望着一场战斗
Forget it. I'm not looking for a fight.
喔  不  不要这样
Oh, no, no, no, no. Don't do that.
如果你要说什么  就说吧
You got something to say, come out and say it.
他是对的 你很虚弱
He's right, you are soft.
我不是说分量
I'm not talking about the weight.
你丢失了底线 你的信心
You've lost your edge, your confidence.
你战败了  李
You lost your war, Lee.
实际上  你是一个渴望战斗的士兵
And the truth is, you're a soldier who needs a war.
你不想听进去 因为你头脑中已经有了
And you don't want to hear it because you've got it in your head
你父亲作为一个战士的形象
that your father's the soldier,
你确定你不想像他一样
and you sure don't want to be like him.
但是你的确像他
But you are like him.
你比你自己知道的更像他
You're more like him than you know.
这就是我嫁给你的原因
That's one of the reasons I married you.
好的  这有效了  我想
Okay, it's working, I think.
这起作用了吗?
Is it working or isn't it?
他们一直在干扰阻塞我们
They keep jamming us.
我们的线人说得非常对
So much for our source on the inside.
还剩下10分钟了 还是什么也没有
Ten minutes left. And lots of nothing on the wireless as usual.
注意赛昂突袭机
Keep an eye out for Raiders.
昨天接听到两声信号  几乎就要抓住它了
The last listening bird almost got popped by a pair yesterday.
我几乎成功了
I've almost got it.
见鬼!  把那个东西关了!
Oh, frak. Turn that thing down.
这起作用了 这起作用了
It's working. It's working.
时间到了 启动FTL  准备离开
Time's up. Spin up the FTL, and get ready to go.
等下 我接收到些东西
Hold on. I'm picking something up.
是殖民地的信号
It's a Colonial transmission.
低能量信号 但识别码是吻合的
It's a low power signal, but the recognition codes match.
是的  我们和地面有联系了
Oh, yeah, we've got a link to the ground.
好的  发送回应码 开启引擎
Okay, send the coded response, spin up the drive,
让我们回到卡拉狄加
and let's get the hell back to Galactica.
我收到一个信号
We've got a signal.
一架猛禽飞机刚刚和我们联系上了
The Raptor just made contact with us.
它说什么?
TIGH: What's it say?
"我们会用这个频率"每12小时联系一次"
"Will make contact this frequency every twelve hours.
"报告当局的军事情报 坚持住 我们来接你们了"
"Prepare sitrep for command authority. Have hope. We're coming for you. "
我再说一次 我们联系上了 我们和地面联系上了
RACETRACK: We made contact! I say again, we made contact with the ground.
泰上校成立了抵抗组织反抗赛昂人
Colonel Tigh has formed an insurgent group against the Cylons,
现在他们已经准备好
and now they're ready and waiting
等待指示怎样来协调救援行动
for instructions on how to coordinate the rescue effort.
这会好的 这真的会好起来的
It's gonna be okay. It's really gonna be okay.
这些都是监视图片 抵抗军拍的
These are the surveillance pictures taken by the insurgents.
我想我可以说出50个照片上的人的名字
I think we can match names to about 50 of these photos,
最乐观估计 警察人数在200左右
but our best guess puts the total police force at around 200.
两百
Two hundred.
我甚至无法相信哪怕只有20个人
I wouldn't have believed there'd be 20 people
会背叛自己的同胞
who would turn against their own kind.
我想要那些名字  我想要其他人的名字
I want those names. I want the rest of the names.
这很困难  赛昂人很害怕民众会追杀
That's tough. The Cylons are afraid the population will go after any human
那些加入新卡布里卡警察部队的人
who joins the New Caprica Police.
他们的确应该被追杀
As well they should.
我知道我的生活不是很好
I know I haven't lived a model life.
我犯了很多错
I made a lot of mistakes.
我今天需要你的庇护
I'm gonna need your protection today.
总统先生
GAETA: Mr. President?
早上好  盖塔
CAPRICA SIX: Good morning, Gaeta.
毕业典礼时间到了
It's time for the graduation ceremony.
是的 典礼
Oh, yes, the ceremony.
关于典礼...计划有变
About the ceremony. There's been a change of plan.
我不会去了
I won't be going.
安全方面的考虑
Security concern.
不要看上去那么担心
Don't look so worried.
那里还会有其他毕业生的
There'll be other graduations.
是的 我只是想让工作人员知道
Right. Okay. I'll just let the staff know.
我们应该取消这个行动
I think we should call off the strike.
如果卡拉狄加要回来了 没有理由去那里
There's no reason to go forward if the Galactica's gonna come back.
什么  拒绝一次杀死盖尤斯・波塔尔的绝佳机会?
What, pass up a golden opportunity to kill Gaius Baltar?
另外  上校  我看不到这样做的意义
Other than that, Colonel, I fail to see the point.
用你的脑子想想  军士长  而不是用你的心
Think with your head, Chief, not with your heart.
他们能够把我们带离这里的唯一机会
The only way they stand a chance of getting us off this rock
就是赛昂人是否能够在他们来这里的时候
is if the Cylons are too distracted battling
被一次全面的战斗所分心
a full-blown uprising when they get here.
好吧  如果内部消息说波塔尔不会去那里  那就取消
All right. If your source on the inside says Baltar's not gonna be there, abort.
不然的话  就继续计划
Otherwise, stick with the plan.
内分泌紊乱或神经性失调
MAN ON SPEAKER: ... hormonal imbalances or neurological disorders.
但在新卡布里卡医疗中心已获得好转..
But many have found relief at the New Caprica medical center
有一只人类和赛昂医学专家组成的队伍在那里
where a crack team of human and Cylon physicians...
嘿  杜克
Hey, Duck.
排队
OFFICER: Fall in!
早上好 欢迎所有的毕业生
Good morning and welcome to all graduates.
你们是希望
You are the hope.
无论对于人类或赛昂来说  你们是明天的希望
You are the dream of a new tomorrow for humans and Cylon alike.
对于你们今天到这来所冒的风险 我向你们致敬
And I salute you for the risks that you have taken for just showing up today.
今天  你们开始了新的职业
Today you begin a new career
作为新生活的临时警官
and a new life as provisional police officers.
透过这所屋子
And looking out across this room,
我看到了那条道路的意义
I see the significance of this new path is not lost on you.
恭喜 很高兴有你加入
Congratulations. It's good to have you with us.
恭喜  警官        危险的任务
Congratulations, Sergeant. A dangerous mission.
恭喜  队长        很高兴有你加入
Congratulations, Captain. It's great to have you with us.
我就来陪你了 Nora
I'll see you soon, Nora.